University of Connecticut, Agricultural Economics Department Records
© 2010 University of Connecticut
- Series IX: Farm Labor Camp, undated, 1943-1947
  - State Farm Labor Report, 1943-1947
  - Farm Labor Employment report, undated
  - Work simplification, undated
  - Connecticut Agricultural Wartime Production Capacity, 1943
  - War Manpower Commission, 1944
  - County agent reports on Farm labor, 1944-1946
  - Conference address on farm labor, 1945
  - Department of Labor - Tobacco Inspection Report, 1946
  - Analysis of Questionnaires - Tobacco supervisors, 1946
  - Training Manual, 1944
  - Connecticut Farm Labor Program, 1943-1944
  - Out-of-State Farm Labor Programs, 1943-1947
- Series X: Youth Labor Camps, undated, 1943-1947
  - Robinson farm labor camp, undated (Box 3)
  - Farm work camps reports, 1943-1947
  - Farm labor camp summary by town, 1947
  - Farm labor camp notebooks, 1946-1947
  - Farm labor camps reports and statistics by town, 1945
  - Farm Labor Camps - Connecticut Department of Health, undated
- Series XI: Women's Land Army, 1942-1945
  - Recruitment brochure, 1942-1943, 1945 (Box 3)
  - Victory Farm Volunteers News letter, 1945
  - Report on VFV dairy course and pickle program, 1944
  - (Box 12)
  - (Box 13)
- Series XII: Extension Services, 1943
  - Cooperative Extension Work for Agricultural and Home Economics, 1943 (Box 3)
- Series XIII: USDA Farm Survey Notes, undated, 1914-1943
  - Subseries A: Record of a Year's business Survey (Geographic), undated, 1914-1936
    - Part time farming information Farm size, acres tilled, crops, stock. Including personal info Number in family, Number on farm age year's farmer. Education: nationality and race, standard of living with Maps. New London County undated, no farm name 18 folders - specific names of farmers Factors to calculate include: Tabulation form Labor Efficiency CT (Box 5)
    - Current expenses notes, capital, receipts from stock products, misc. receipts, livestock summary efficiency factors, value of buildings, depreciation charges, Milk rec'd, working capital labor, crops, acres, labor income, man work units, profits, personal info: (education) CAC Operator, Capital, General expenses, receipts from stock purchases, misc. receipts efficiency factors; Summary crops, stock, crops, yield operator sales, landlord sales, operator livestock, landlord livestock, machinery, receipts, education, crop rotation; Map - Lebanon, daily time record home management studies, census, typewritten tables, bulletin, value per acre, agriculture instruction, 1914-17, 1924 (Box 6)
  - Subseries B: Apple Marketing, 1931-1943
    - (Box 17)
    - (Box 43)
    - (Box 48)
    - (Box 50)
  - Subseries C: Egg Marketing
    - (Box 43)
    - (Box 44)
  - Subseries D: County agent reports, 1916-1930
    - (Box 20)
    - (Box 21)
    - (Box 27)
  - Subseries E: Farm Administration Survey, 1927-1929
    - Agricultural economics farm management county agent report; photo, farm fair pamphlet, "The farm home maker" agricultural report, photos quantitative and narrative photos, 1927-1929 (Box 21)
  - Subseries F: Tobacco Survey, 1926-1930
    - (Box 15)
    - (Box 24)
    - (Box 25)
    - (Box 53)
- Series XIV: State of Connecticut Farm Economics Agricultural Survey
  - Subseries A: Farm Economics Agricultural Survey, 1913-1922
    - Values: dairy productions, eggs, crops, receipts, expenses (plus) personal info: CT ag econ nationality, occupation, family, age standard of living; Chesnutt Hill, Colchester, Lenanon, Bozrahville, Leonard's Bridge, 1922 (Box 8)
    - New London, North Franklin, Willimantic, 1913-1916 (Box 9)
    - Hours of manual labor, 1927 (Box 59-60)
    - 1934 (Box 62-63)
  - Subseries B: Workers Association Part-time farming survey, 1923-1935
    - (Box 9)
- Series XV: Federal and State marketing surveys
  - Subseries A: Dairy, Eastern Connecticut Poultry Producers (ECPP), undated, 1921-1941
    - (Box 7)
    - (Box 18)
    - Box 35 includes SNET report on business conditions (Box 35-36)
    - Dairy Study (Box 38-41)
  - Subseries B: Fruits and Vegetables, 1919-1944
    - (Box 18)
    - (Box 37)
    - (Box 51-52)
    - (Box 65-66)
  - Subseries C: Farmers' Exchange Feed Prices, 1919-1930
    - Newspaper clippings, "Roadside stand disapproved for farm produce", 1919, 1927, 1930 (Box 33-34)
  - Subseries D: USDA Fluid Milk report, 1921-1943
    - (Box 35)
- Series XVI: Connecticut Agricultural College, undated, 1920-1959
  - Subseries A: Questionnaires, undated
    egg laying contest, tariffs, dairy, poultry, census; Newspaper clipping - Davis Newspaper clipping, Davis 1925 Foreigners on farms: "Need Americanizing" agriculturally, socially, politically, Storrs Bulletin State AG. Ext
    - Department files, 1930s; ag school fino Small red BOX "data on the Lebanon SURVEY Ag Econ "Inside: index cards age, percent of area, income (labor / family) rec'd hens, horses Results are recorded quantitatively mathematically, 1920 (Box Index card box)
  - Subseries B: Farm Management report, 1926-1944
    - Corn belt (Box 7)
    - 1920s (Box 8)
    - 1930s (Box 9)
    - Wholesale Specialized farms, 1933-1935 (Box 10-11)
    - 1927-1950 (Box 13)
    - 1924-1943 (Box 14)
    - Includes farm income and expenses, earnings and performance (Box 16)
    - 1927-1951 (Box 19)
    - Suffield county, 1926 (Box 22-23)
    - 1936 (Box 26)
    - Tolland, Hartford and New London counties (Box 27)
    - 1924-50 (Box 28-32)
    - 1936-1940 (Box 42)
    - 1940s (Box 45)
    - 1931 (Box 49)
    - 1937-1950 (Box 54-55)
    - 1937-1950 (Box 61)
    - 1937-1950 (Box 64)
    - 1937-1950 (Box 67)
    - 1937-1950 (Box 71)
  - Subseries C: Record Keeping, 1918-1946
    - Farm Survey Data Reports, Documentation, farm census, maps blueprints, surveys, GLASS PLATES 1918-1938 farm data photo plates, women canning, children in garden (to show height of corn?), picnic, chicks, pigs, four children on porch, sheep club, sweaters made from yarn, baseball game, demonstration by ct. club members, 4H club women, state sewing club corset cover, apron, cap hem stitched towels, Boston poultry show, class photo, junior short course class photo, junior food army, Goshen fair, banquet, News clippings market men plan war on parking, blue prints, Reports, 1946 New Haven, fruits trees by town, census, commodities stats, veggie prices, price studies, surveys, athletic council college fundraising, recording of digging potatoes, cost of growing potatoes, account books. (Box 37)
  - Subseries D: Home Economics Administration
    - Supervisor weekly and monthly reports, 1948-50, committee on 4H history, conference notes, rural youth committee, itineraries, child nutrition, education materials, interview notes, recording of method demonstrations given, circulations, training local leaders, food preparation narrative reports. (Box 69-70)
  - Subseries E: I. G. Davis, 1920s
    - Correspondence (Box 29)
  - Subseries F: Department of Economics Administration, 1923-1930s
    - Press releases, 1956-1962 (Box 68)
    - Scantic County, MA, tree farms soil conservation service, 1931-1940 (Box 56-58)
      Bulletin, surveys, financial statements, lists of farms, services data, blueprints, data, plan of conservation operations, directions for working schedules, summary sheets, Land ownership data, photos (tobacco leaf, potatoes, soil depletion, farm wreckage from hurricane, tobacco shed, seminars, charts, code sheet, directions for summary sheet, data, tax, outline (Intro: "studies in the econ of soil conservation have been in progress in ct since 1938 originally, I.G. Davis personally supervised the project since his death in early 1939), newspaper clippings, correspondence Surveys, (Family living information: human resources and living age stopped going to school; Grade, nationality; parent living standard as shown by number of rooms; Number in household; Electric lights; Running water; Bath complete; Sewage disposal; Screen; Radio, auto, refrigerator, Outside appearance 1, 2,3 4, Health of farmer.
    - Financial Records, Connecticut Valley Tobacco Association, undated
      Trial balances of expense accounts; Account ledger books, charts.